Saurabh Bajaj

saurabhbsd@gmail.com +91-8000888022

http://saurabhbajaj.me

Summary

I am an experienced iOS application engineer currently working in Pune, India. I like to come up with simple solutions to difficult problems. Code quality, maintainability and pragmatism are my core programming principles. Being an iOS engineer, I give great attention to the UX and UI of the project.

EDUCATION

Decarion	
Master in Computer Applications	Aug 2013 - Apr 2015
University of Pune, Pune	
Bachelor in Computer Applications	July 2010 - Apr 2013
University of Pune, Pune	
CERTIFICATIONS	
Diploma in iOS Application Development Sourcekode Technologies, Pune	June 2014 - Aug 2014
Career History	

Career History

Team Lead - iOS, Sell.do, Pune

Sept 2018 - Present

- Enriching the product application with new features and enhancements.
- Managing resources and ensuring timely development and delivery of application with minimal bugs.
- Interact with sales and support team for gathering requirements and collecting feedbacks from clients.

iOS Developer, Promobi Technologies, Pune

Nov 2015 - Sept 2018

- Own the complete product life-cycle from architecting to implementation and App Store release management.
- Worked on app performance optimisation by using profiling tools in Xcode.

iOS Developer - Intern, Emerson Innovation Center, Pune

Jan 2015 - Aug 2015

• Worked on a Bluetooth based application in Objective-C.

Apps

Sell.Do: A CRM tool for real estate.

Handwerker Station: An ecommerce app.

Brew Survey: A mobile survey and feedback solution. **Booster:** A snapshot of your finances at your fingertips.

Naki: An innovative tech based laundry service.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Swift, SwiftUI, Objective-C, C++, C, Python(minor experience)

Database: SQLite Version Control: Git

Libraries and Frameworks: Cocoa Touch, AVFoundation, CoreData, CoreBluetooth, Map kit, Firebase,

Fabric

Mobile Development: Native iOS Development

Operating Systems: macOS, Windows

Important links

Github: https://github.com/saurabhbajajcode

 ${\bf Linkedin}: \ {\rm https://www.linkedin.com/in/saurabhbajajcode/}$

 ${\bf Twitter: https://twitter.com/saurabhbajaj91}$

ACHIEVEMENTS AND VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE

Spotlight award in the Innovate category: Internal award from Sell.do office

Volunteer, City Level Walkathon: Green Run, Lohgaon, Pune

Dec 2019

Volunteer, National level Conference : Sinhgad Institute of Management and Computer Applications, (Pune) Feb 2015